# **Ahmy Yulrizka**

# Senior Software Engineer

**ADDRESS** 

**NATIONALITY** 

Musicallaan 155, Utrecht, 3543EC,

The Netherlands

Indonesian

EMAIL LINKS yulrizka@gmail.com

github.com/yulrizka, linkedin.com/in/yulrizka, labs.yulrizka.com

#### **Profile**

I have More than 11 years of experience with software development. I involved in the design, architect, and implement high throughput systems serving traffic for one of the top popular sites in the Netherlands.

As part of a team, my potential contributions would be to collaborate with the team and business to rapidly iterate on the design and implementation of new functionalities and also maintain, improve and scale the current system.

Main skill set:

**Programming Languages**: Golang, ruby, python, java **Databases**: MySQL, Cassandra, Clickhouse, Redis

Queues: Kafka, ActiveMQ, RabbitMQ

Deployments: Hashistack (Nomad, Terraform, Consul), Openstack, salt, puppet

# **Employment History**

Aug 2015 - Present

AMSTERDAM, THE NETHERLANDS

# Lead Software Engineer

eBay Classified Group/Marktplaats

I started working as a software developer. My role then was to design and implement multiple micro-services to support high-throughput systems. Currently, leading the platform sub-team which focuses on closing the gap between developers and operations with automation.

**Key technologies**: Go, MySQL, Clickhouse, Elasticsearch, HashiStack (consul, nomad), Kafka, Redis

#### Responsibilities:

- · Leading migration from running on bare metal to a scheduled environment in the cloud.
- · Leading migration from legacy search engine to Elasticsearch.
- · Design and implement an asynchronous image processing pipeline.
- · Involved in designing a high throughput analytic engine.
- · Represent my team in the Architect Group.

Jun 2012 — Jul 2015

ROTTERDAM, THE NETHERLANDS

#### Software Engineer

Sense Observation Systems

Sense OS is a start-up that focuses on providing IOT platform with an intelligent agent that empowers developers to build smart applications. My main role is to expand and scale the back-end system

**Key technologies**: Go, PHP, Ruby & Rails, Cassandra, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS (EC2, Route53, S3), Openstack, Kafka, Redis, ELK Stack, Chef, Android (java), iOS (Swift & Objective-C). Frontend (JS, Angular, CSS, Haml, Compass, Sass)

#### Responsibilities:

- · Scale the platform by designing and implementing microservices
- Evaluate, implement and maintain message queuing architecture that enables real-time processing
- Design and implement real time monitoring allowing insight and immediate action upon system disruption.
- Deploy automation allowing easy and fast deployment and the ability to switch cloud providers which provides cost-effective, high available system.
- · Take part in mobile development both Android and iOS.
- · Fronted development for dashboard application.

Jan 2009 — Jan 2012 BANDUNG, INDONESIA

## **Chief Technology Officer**

PT Stargle Indonesia

Starqle is a small startup that mainly develops software for company and government institutions.

Key technologies: Ruby (and rails, sinatra), Java (hibernate, JBoss Seam), PHP, MySQL, Git, SVN

#### Responsibilities:

- · Responsible for determining framework and architecture used for Development.
- · Lead a team as project managers on several projects.
- · Establish policy and development workflow with test-driven development.
- Identify and explore new technology and project management that would be suitable for projects.

Mar 2008 - Jan 2009

BANDUNG, INDONESIA

## Software Developer

PT. Zamrud Khatulistiwa Technology

Zamrud Khatilistiwa Techonloy is a software company that develop custom solutions for private companies. I started as a junior software developer.

#### Responsibilities:

- Lead programmer crayonpedia.org. Customizing mediawiki engines to create an encyclopedia that follows the national school curriculum.
- · As a developer of financial systems for the local state government.
- As a developer of administration support systems used by one of the national agencies.
- Establish policies and software version control systems to enable collaborative development.

Key technologies: Javascript (Extjs), PHP, Java (Spring, DWR, Hibernate), Mysql, Subversion

## **Education**

Institut Teknologi Bandung

#### Master of Information System

Major: Information Systems

- · Software Engineering, Information Engineering, Enterprise Process & Modeling.
- Strategic Information Planning, Strategy & Policy of Information System.
- · Management of Information System, Information System Governance.
- · Risk Management of Information System, Project & Change Management

2004 - 2008

**BANDUNG** 

# Institut Teknologi Bandung

Bachelor of Informatics

Major: Information System

- · Algorithm & Data Structure, Algorithmic Strategies, Internet Programming
- · Object Oriented Programming, Object Oriented Analysis & Design
- · Database System, Operating System, System Programming
- · Software Engineering, Software Project Management
- · Wireless Mobile Computing

## **Licenses & Certificates**

Mar 2017 - Present

DATASTAX

DataStax Certified Professional on DataStax Enterprise (Cassandra, Spark, DSE Search, DSE Graph)

Credential ID: 952c0c8f-5047-4eaa-a9c6-033aca4ea8c8

https://academy.datastax.com/

Dec 2015 - Present

COURSERA

Machine Learning

Credential ID: HXSL3KT2GRP8

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/HXSL3KT2GRP8

Nov 2013 - Nov 2015

AMAZON WEB SERVICE

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate Level

Credential ID: AWS-ASA-1810

http://aws.amazon.com/certification/

Languages

English

Indonesian

••••

Dutch

